RUBEN ORMENO LOPEZ

DNI: 40891398 95 Ferncliffe Crescent. Markham. Ontario. Canada. Telf. +14167313470 yormeno@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced computer engineer with MBA degree and PMP certification focused on transforming business requirements into system solutions, conferencing with clients, defining their requirements, develop and deploy the applications to production environment. Creative person, proactive and strong sense of ownership of projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PS Consultant Jan 2019-Dec2022

Genesys Telecommunication Laboratories, Inc.

- Upgraded the voice media applications in redhat 7.9 linux operation system in order to provide more functionalities for a telecommunication company in Brasil.
- Created a new service to generate callbacks as a customer demand by adding a new Rest API endpoint, manage some configurations and make testing with the client.
- Developed an assessment of the applications and infrastructure of the client's contact center generating a report with recommendations and best practices to implement in order to improve their performance.
- Defined the scope of the project with the client and building a new service to connect customer whatsapps with a customizable bot for other customers. (Windows server 2016, MSSQLServer 2017, Genesys GIA and DMS)
- Developed an IVR for the biggest Peruvian Bank and integrate it with Rest API endpoints from the bank to provide balances, last movements and payment dates of the customer credit cards. (Apache groovy, Genesys GIA, Rest APIs, vxml).
- Supported and resolved issues on IVR integrated with Google Speech to Text, Google Text to Speech and IBM Watson bot from a telecommunication company of Argentina.
- Participated in the definition and implementation of the contact center of the biggest peruvian bank.
 Creating a omnichannel for the communication of the customer with the bank. Their employees of
 customer services can now talk, chat and attend email using a single application. Also telemarketing and
 collecting areas can have automate dialing campaigns to contact customers. (Integrating 120 host servers
 in windows and linux, Cassandra, MSSQL Server 2016, TLS1.2 communication, Genesys 9.0, sip
 protocols)

Co-founder / Project Manager / Consultant GOSCorp Peru

May 2013 – Dec 2018

Apr 2012 – Apr 2013

- Supervised and implemented the chat application in a Colombian telecommunication company to connect with their customers.
- Managed the support services provided by the company complying with the service level defined in the contract. The support service was for the contact center of a retail company from 3 countries: Peru, Chile, Argentina and Colombia.
- Managed the training of the team to keep them updated and certified in Genesys applications.
- Managed developing projects in javascript for the IVR of telecommunications companies and PHP web to customize some features.
- Presented and proposed new services to prospective clients.
- Created job descriptions and posted on websites to attract new candidates.

Business Solution-2
Everis Peru

03/02/2023

- Tech lead of the team to support and develop new features of the customer that was a bank
- kept the 6 members team updated with the new features of Genesys applications to give the support service.
- Helped and supported the team to resolve the issues quickly.
- kept the contact center platform up 99% the 24 hours of the 7 days of the weeks according to the contract.

Deputy assistant manager of application analysis

Nov 2009 – Mar 2012

Credit Bank of Peru

- Conferenced with the users, defined their requirements and followed the software development cycle to implement the needs of the business.
- Evaluated if the project would be developed with intern resources or with software development providers.
- Negotiated the contracts with the software development providers.
- Advised the purchase of the equipment and technological resources of the contact center bank.
- Managed the implementation of the high availability of the contact center of the bank.
- Assured the quality of the new software releases in the contact center bank.

Developer Engineer

Jan 2006 - Jan 2009

Telectronic Peru.

- Analyzed the requirements of the client, designed and developed web pages for one of the biggest Peruvian bank. (Used JSP with Struts framework and MSSQL Server 2000).
- Analyzed the requirements of the client, designed and deployed the Genesys contact center in telecommunications companies. (JSP, strut framework, Oracle database 10g).
- Improved telemarketing and collecting areas of the banks to automate the dialing campaigns to contact their customers. (Using dialogic PCI cards)

SKILLS

- Ability to guickly learn and implement the standards or/and software tools.
- Efficient communication skills for transferring the scope of the project to all role levels with clearly ideas and statements.
- Ability to analyze complex technical information.
- Ability to analyze business requirements and assess impact within whole system architecture.
- Strong problem-solving skills.
- Ability to troubleshoot and debug applications.
- Ability to identify and manage key stakeholders.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree in Strategic Business Administration

Feb 2011 – Dec 2012

Pontificial Catholic University of Peru

Bachelor's Degree in Science, Major in Computer Engineer

Aug 1999 – Jul 2006

Pontificial Catholic University of Peru

CERTIFICATIONS

03/02/2023

Agile Scrum Master (Exin Certificate)

Cobit 5 Foundation GR692004954RO

Project Management Professional (PMP® #1745763)

Since Aug 2014

03/02/2023